原创翻译  双语字幕
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
《沼泽怪物》前情回顾
Previously on Swamp Thing...
你好  艾比  天哪  你没事真是太好了
Hello, Abby. God, I am so relieved that you are okay.
-别这样  -艾比  如果这是因为
- Don't. - Oh, Abby, if this is about
玛丽亚袭击了你...
Maria attacking you like that...
你应该去死
You should be dead!
我真不知道她是怎么了
I honestly don't know what got into her.
-真抱歉我当时没...  -住嘴
- I'm just sorry I wasn't there-- - Stop.
为了保护你  我夺走了一个人的性命
I took a man's life to protect you.
德博阿  他看见你了
Dubois, he fuckin' saw you.
你炸了霍兰的船
You took out Holland's boat.
你在说什么  你了解我的
What are you taking about? You know me!
我也了解埃弗里·桑德兰
And I know Avery Sunderland.
霍兰肯定妨碍到了他
Holland must've been in his way,
所以他需要除掉他
which means he needed him gone.
于是他找了一个他可以信任的人
So he found somebody he could trust,
一个他知道会保密的人
somebody he knew would keep their damn mouth shut.
丹尼尔·卡西迪苏醒了
Daniel Cassidy regained consciousness.
这都是因为你用艾比从沼泽里拿来的样本
And this happened because you spun a magic potion
制作了一种魔法药水
from the sample Abby took out of the swamp.
我现在就给你一项能改变世界的发现
I'm giving you a discovery that could change the world.
有个陌生人来沼泽找我
A stranger came to me in the swamp.
他希望我仔细研究
He wants me to look more
环绕着我的万物之绿
deeply into this green that surrounds me.
-那是什么  -我不确定
- What's that? - I'm not sure.
亚历克
Alec.
艾比
Abby?
我...我不明白
I just... I don't understand.
这怎么可能呢
How is any of this possible?
我觉得你吸入的孢子
I think the spore you inhaled
大概有致幻作用
had some hallucinogenic property or something.
-你不是真的...  -对  我还是...
- You're not actually-- - No, no, I'm still...
抱歉  突然感觉很奇怪
Sorry. It's suddenly so weird
就这样注视着你的眼睛...
to just be staring in the eyes of...
从前那个迷人的我
The charming man I used to be.
是的
Yeah.
这种幻觉会持续多久
And how long will this hallucination last?
一分钟  一年  我不知道
A minute, a year. I have no clue.
我是说  这是我无意识中做到的
I mean, it's not like I'm doing this consciously.
仿佛是新的世界  环绕着我们的万物之绿
It's like this new world. This green all around us.
它会对我的想法和感觉做出反应
It's like it reacts to my thoughts and my feelings and...
我觉得它感受到了
I think it sensed how much
我有多么想让你再次看到我原本的样子
I wanted you to see me as myself again.
我有多么  渴望我们之间的关系
You know, how much I, uh, longed for that connection.
那么...
So, uh...
有什么可以招待你的吗
Can I get you something?
既然你提起来了
You know, now that you mention it,
我从昨天早上起
I haven't actually eaten anything
就没吃过东西了  所以我...
since yesterday morning, so I--
不不不  这可不行
No, no, no, no, that won't do.
这里可能有些饼干
There may be some crackers over here.
亚历克
Alec?
好吧
All right.
看来我们这有些番石榴  李子
Well, looks like we got some guava, plums,
-来个芒果怎么样  -李子吧
- mango maybe. - Uh, plum.
李子
Plum.
味道如何
What's the verdict?
太好吃了
It's so good!
这些都是你凭空变出来的吗
Okay, so you can just make this happen out of thin air?
我只是担心你肚子饿了  然后万物之绿...
I was just concerned about you being hungry, and the green...
好吧  替我感谢万物之绿
Well, tell the green thank you very much.
这个  这个太好吃了
This is, this is... It's delicious.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
一切都开始苏醒了
Everything is starting to wake up.
浮萍  锯齿草  夹竹桃花
Duckweed, sawgrass, phlox flower.
还有那些野葛  吵人的家伙们  天啊
And all those kudzu, noisy bastards. Jeez.
你能听到植物苏醒吗
You can hear the plants waking up?
植物比动物更加敏感
Plants are much more sensitive than animals.
只是它们的声音更小一些
Their voices are just a little quieter.
它们想要告诉我什么
And they're trying to tell me something.
是关于"黑暗"的
About the "Darkness"?
这世上有太多超乎想象的美  艾比
God, there's so much unimaginable beauty out there, Abby.
太多的死亡
So much death.
我看到了很多  那些被腐朽侵占的地方
I've seen things, places where the rot and decay have taken over
摧毁了所有生命  吞噬途经的一切
and destroyed all life, consuming everything in its path.
带我去
Show me.
不管是什么控制了你  都是在沼泽诞生的
Whatever's gotten a hold you, it was born in the swamp.
我需要了解这个黑暗
I need to understand this darkness,
这个"腐朽"  这样我才有机会治愈你
this, this "rot", if I'm ever gonna cure you.
不  艾比
No, Abby!
艾比  艾比  等一下
Abby! Abby, wait up.
该死  等一等  等等  停下  听着
Damn it! Just wait a minute. Wait. Stop. Listen.
进入被腐朽
Entering this area,
掌控的地区非常危险
where the rot has taken over, is very dangerous.
好的  但危险的植物有时候能产出
Okay, and dangerous plants can sometimes produce
-最有效的药物  -我明白
- the most effective medicine. - I understand that.
相信我
And believe me,
没人比我更想被治愈  相信我
no one wants that medicine more than I do, trust me,
但是不能冒着让你丧命的风险
but not at the risk of losing your life.
我是疾控中心的医生  这是我本职
I am a CDC doctor. This is what I do.
我们要去
We're going.
翻译  布塔
翻译  DustD
翻译  冰岛豆腐
翻译  survor
翻译  Sakura的小书包
翻译  Serrino
翻译  DerbyNinja
翻译  余欢
翻译  沼泽小鱼人
翻译  iLOST
翻译  屯栗子
翻译  管家大愚
时间轴  紫夏
时间轴  西·查
校对  布塔槽多无口
校对  Sakura的小书包
校对  屯栗子
后期  渔夫
字幕总监制  布塔
沼泽   怪物
第一季  第七集
警长办公室里没咖啡了吗
Sherriff's department run out of Folgers?
只是想换个环境
Just felt like a change of scenery.
调岗请求
Transfer request.
这可比从吧台搬到卡座的距离远多了
That's more than moving from the bar to a booth.
糖用完了
You're out of sugar.
好吧  不关我事
All right. None of my business.
我在警讯监控仪听到  你和几名警探
So, the police scanner placed you and a couple of detectives
昨晚深入沼泽
deep in the swamp last night,
寻找袭击那两名猎人的坏蛋
looking for the bad boy who attacked those hunters.
找到了吗
Any luck?
或许你该问艾比
Maybe you should ask Abby.
我也想  但我今早还没见过她
I would, except I haven't seen her this morning.
你不会碰巧知道她在哪吧
Don't suppose you happen to know where she's at?
你不用藏着掖着  莉茲
You don't have to keep hiding it, Liz.
艾比肯定已经跟你说了
I'm sure Abby already told you.
跟我说...
Told me...
-亚历克·霍兰的事  -他怎么了
- About Alec Holland. - What about him?
我看到他了  莉茲  我什么都知道了
Look, I've seen him, Liz. I know everything.
你看到他了  艾比呢
You've seen him? And Abby?
他们还好吗
Are they all right?
别担心  上次我看到他们的时候  他们都没事
Don't worry. Last time I saw them, they were fine.
但艾比在保护他  她还认为她能
But Abby's protecting him. She still thinks she can...
我也不知道  让他"回来"
I don't know, bring him back.
马特  我认识你多久了
Matt, how long have I known you?
三年级就认识了  珀金老师的课上
Third grade, Mr. Perkin's class.
我太了解你了  这幅愁眉苦脸的样子不是你
Long enough to know this pensive thing isn't you.
你有什么事瞒着我
What is it you're not telling me?
我很害怕
I'm scared.
艾比一直在说玛雷有一股黑暗力量
Abby keeps talking about this darkness in Marais,
说什么沼泽里
like there's this poison
释放出了毒物
coming off the swamp, you know?
你觉得她听上去像是疯子
And you're thinking she sounds crazy.
更糟
Worse.
我觉得她是对的
I'm thinking she's right.
我不明白  我跟伍德罗说了别搞这么多数字
I don't understand it. I told Woodrue to go easy on the numbers.
你雇用伍德罗博士  因为他是最出色的
Well, you hired Dr. Woodrue because he's the best.
不代表他通俗易懂
Doesn't mean he's easy to understand.
嗯  不  亲爱的  你不必做这些的
Yeah. No, honey, you didn't have to do all this.
我可以找餐饮公司
I would have been happy bringing in a caterer.
埃勒里先生这样的人习惯了吃宴席
A man like Mr. Ellery is used to catered meals.
但他八成很少吃家常菜
What he probably doesn't have much of is home cooking.
有可能
Well, that could be.
他开的药
That medication he prescribed,
好像让你有精神多了
it really seems to be lifting your spirits.
是的  我感觉很放松
It's true. I feel so... relaxed.
你对这个内森·埃勒里先生有什么了解
So, what do you know about this Mr. Nathan Ellery anyway?
几乎不了解  他似乎喜欢这样
Very little, which seems to be the way he likes it.
我只知道他是秘密会议集团的高级顾问
I just know that he's senior advisor for the Conclave Group.
秘密会议集团
Conclave Group.
像是间谍小说里才有的东西
Sounds like something out of a spy novel.
我只知道他们给各种各样的初创公司
All I know is they've given hundreds of millions
提供了数亿的资金  医疗  制药
to all kinds of start-ups. Healthcare, pharmaceuticals,
武器开发  航空航天
weapons development, aerospace.
我让娜丁准备一壶萨泽拉克鸡尾酒
Well, I asked Nadine to whip up a pitcher of Sazerac,
很适合搭配开胃小菜
which will pair nicely with the canapes,
然后上杏仁鳟鱼
and then, we'll move on to trout amandine,
香煎法罗和芥菜
pan fried farro and mustard greens.
瞧瞧你
Look at you!
俨然是南方美女
Playing the Southern belle.
肯定是弗洛伊德送兰花来了
That must be Floyd with the orchids.
桑德兰先生  警长找你
Mr. Sunderland, the Sheriff would like a word.
桑德兰夫人
Mrs. Sunderland.
凯博警长  真是惊喜啊
Sheriff Cable. What a surprise.
抱歉打扰你们
I'm sorry to interrupt y'all,
但我找你有点事  埃弗里
but I need to borrow you for a minute, Avery.
警方事务
Police business.
你去吧  我还有点事要忙
You go on. I've got a few things to sort out.
那好
Well...
我跟你说过多少遍了
I've told you a hundred times
永远不要不打招呼就来我家
never to come here without calling.
王八蛋
You son of a bitch!
你想让霍兰死
You wanted him dead,
但你自己没胆量动手
but you didn't have the guts to do it yourself
所以你就要挟马特是吗
so you blackmailed Matt?
你把我儿子拽进了一起谋杀
You dragged my son into a fucking murder.
我早该知道
I should have known that
这小子口风不严
mama's boy couldn't keep his mouth shut.
我一直都知道你身体里住着毒蛇  埃弗里
I always knew that a part of you was like a goddamn snake, Avery.
但我从未  从未想过它会来咬我
I never, ever thought that snake was coming after me.
但事实是  一旦跟你扯上关系就会万劫不复
But the truth is, everything you touch goes to hell,
这个镇子  我  马特
this town, me, Matt.
最糟糕的是  整整三十年
And the worst part about it is for 30 years,
我一直对此坐视不理
I just stood by and let it all happen.
是啊  可我怎么不记得你之前抱怨过
Yeah, well, I don't recall you complaining
那时候  我的这些勾当可给你赚了大钱呢
when all my dirty business was lining your pockets.
去你的  埃弗里
Fuck you, Avery.
不如这样  等你不再趾高气昂了
I'll tell you what, when you come off your high horse,
就自己过来
why don't you come over here
喝杯酒  然后走人吧
and make yourself a drink then show yourself out.
我还有个会要准备
I got a meeting to prepare for.
准备个屁  这事还没完
The hell you do. This isn't finished.
你这话什么意思
What are you talking about?
亚历克·霍兰还活着
Alec Holland is alive.
胡扯
Bullshit!
他不可能活下来
No way he survived.
马特看见他了
Matt saw him.
说他受到那种植物疾病的衍生影响而变得畸形
He says he's been deformed by some offshoot of that plant disease,
但的确是霍兰  我告诉你
but it's Holland all right. And I'll tell you,
如果他回到镇上说出真相
if he gets to town and starts talking,
我们三个都会因凶杀和共谋而锒铛入狱
all three of us are going down for murder and conspiracy.
我会处理的
I'll handle it.
不  这件事上你别想全身而退
Oh, no. You will not vomit out your dirty work on this one.
我们要一起处理  你和我  现在就去
We're gonna do this, you and me, right now.
-你疯了  -不  我是在保护儿子
- You're out of your mind. - No, I'm protecting my son.
这件事没有商量的余地
And this is not a negotiation.
我是在告诉你接下来该怎么做
This is me telling you how it's gonna go down.
霍兰  还活着
Holland. Alive...
见鬼
Shit!
-还顺利吗  -是的  抱歉
- Everything okay? - Yeah, I'm sorry.
出了点事情  我要出去一会儿
Something's come up, and I gotta go out for a bit.
露西莉亚需要我帮忙游说某位法官
Lucilia needs me to smooth things over with a certain judge...
我们的客人七点才来
Our guests shouldn't be until 7:00,
我肯定能及时赶回来
so I'll be back in plenty of time.
好  没问题
Well, all right.
娜丁和我会准备好一切
Nadine and I will make sure that everything's ready.
好的
Okay.
我会让他尽快回到你身边  桑德兰夫人
I'll get him back home to you as soon as I can, Mrs. Sunderland.
好
All right.
Okay.
我从小在玛雷长大
I've spent my entire childhood in Marais,
在这片沼泽里度过了很多时间
hours in this swamp,
却不曾见过这般郁郁葱葱的景象
and I don't think I've seen it this lush before.
李子结出  鲜花盛开
Plums appear, flowers bloom.
怎么会出现这样的奇景
How is any of this happening?
这有点难以解释
It's, uh... It's a little hard to explain.
我只知道这个地方
Only that it's not connected to a world
完全不遵循任何逻辑
that has anything to do with logic.
也不遵循科学
Or science.
科学是真实且深奥的
Well, science is real, it's profound,
但我现在知道了世上还存在着其他
but now I know that there's other parts of this world
和科学一样深奥而自然的部分
that are just as profound, just as natural.
比如万物之绿
Like the green.
不止于此  还有一些无形的力量
It's more than that. There are these unseen forces
环绕在我们身边
that play all around us.
生死之力
Forces of life and death.
在最理想的状况下
In the best of times,
生死之力互相调和
they work against each other in a, kind of, harmony.
保持平衡
Keeping a balance.
然后在某时某地
And then, there are times and places
更黑暗的元素  死亡与腐朽
where the darker elements, the death and the rot.
会压倒和抑制万物之绿
It takes over, drowns out the green.
什么声音
What was that?
是树
It's trees.
它们很痛苦
They're in pain.
天哪
Oh, my God.
电锯  毒素以及有人一直在倒入的促进剂
Chainsaws, toxins, the accelerant someone's been dumping.
树在愤怒地控诉
It's lashing out in anger.
你要做什么
What are you doing?
-我需要取样带回实验室  -不行
- I need to get a sample to take back to the lab. - No.
如果这就是影响玛雷的生物异常现象的根源
If this is the source of the biological anomalies affecting Marais,
-我们需要弄清楚  -你没在听我说
- we need to understand it. - You're not listening to me.
我们不能再往前走了  太危险了
We're not going any further. It's too dangerous.
-那里可能蕴含着丰富的知识  -艾比
- There could be a wealth of knowledge in there... - Abby.
或许能帮助我们研制出解药
that could lead us towards a cure.
取不到样本的话我是不会回去的
I'm not going back without a specimen.
艾比
Abby.
-桑德兰夫人  -博士
- Mrs. Sunderland. - Doctor.
我们得谈谈
We have to talk.
如果你是来告知我今晚的着装要求的
Well, if this is about tonight's dress code,
卡洛琳向我保证我会穿着合适的服装出席
Caroline assures me that I'll be in proper attire.
其实我是希望能和你聊聊你的研究
Actually, I was hoping we could talk about your work.
我一直在读你的报告
I've been going over your report,
我希望能在晚宴上进行的流畅的交流
and I like to keep the conversation moving at the dinner table.
我不太理解你得出的结论
I was having a little trouble understanding your conclusions.
我的报告不是写给外行人看的  桑德兰夫人
I don't write for a lay audience, Mrs. Sunderland.
如果你的丈夫想让复杂的生物化学
If your husband wants complex biochemistry
变得更容易理解
distilled down into something more digestible,
-那我或许可以...  -抱歉
- then perhaps I could, uh-- - I'm sorry.
我应该说得更清楚一些的
I should have been more clear.
令我感到困惑的不是科学
It wasn't the science that I was confused by,
而是你认为自己的测试
it was the part where you deemed your testing
取得了绝对成功的那部分
an unmitigated success.
从昏迷中被你唤醒的那个人
The man you revived from a coma
现在被捆在轮床上  痛苦地扭动着
left here strapped to a gurney, writhing in pain.
副作用总是过程的一部分  桑德兰太太
Side effects are always part of the process, Mrs. Sunderland.
如果我有一个更大的患者库可供选择
Perhaps if I had had a wider patient pool to select from,
也许我们就不用谈这个了
then we wouldn't be having this conversation.
博士  你不必那么戒备我
You don't have to be defensive with me, Doctor.
我只是想知道
I just wanna know.
如果时间和金钱不是问题
If time and money weren't an issue,
你有信心实现自己的承诺吗
are you confident you could achieve what you're promising here?
我们到底为什么要谈这些
Why are we even having this conversation?
埃弗里在哪里
Where's Avery?
埃弗里现在不在
Avery isn't here right now.
在他回来之前  你听命于我
Until he returns, you'll be answering to me.
能还是不能
Yes or no?
你有信心实现自己的承诺吗
Are you confident you can deliver what you're promising here?
毫无疑问
No doubt in my mind.
晚餐七点开始
Dinner's at 7:00.
别迟到了
Don't be late.
带这么多弹药来对付一个叛逃的科学家
Some heavy duty ammo for a renegade scientist.
上次猎枪和炸药都没能弄死霍兰
Holland walked away from a shotgun and dynamite the last time.
我不会冒险
I'm not taking any chances.
天啊  埃弗里  你为什么非得杀了他
Jesus, Avery, why did you have to go kill him?
那个王八蛋犯了个错误
That son of a bitch made one mistake.
什么错误
What was that?
霍兰知道自己在做什么
Holland knew what he was doing.
如果他能老实做他的工作
If he just stuck to his job, you know?
进行测试  提交报告
Run his test, filed his reports.
但他越界了
But he overstepped.
管他不该管的闲事
Stuck his nose where it didn't belong.
想想如果他知道了
Well, imagine if he knew
这些年来你倾倒废料  过度砍伐
about all the years that you were dumping and over-logging,
以及炸新水道的事  想象一下
and dynamiting new channels, imagine that.
因为我父亲的事  这片沼泽仍然亏欠我太多
The swamp still owes me a lot for my father.
你知道的
You know that.
霍兰差点就毁了
Holland was about to destroy
我的毕生心血
everything that I spent my entire life trying to achieve,
以及我一直努力为玛雷镇
all the prosperity I've been working my ass off
带来的一切繁荣
to bring to this town, to Marais.
你说的是你用于中饱私囊的繁荣吗
You mean all the prosperity you've been putting in your back pocket?
还有给那些
And all that fucking money
曾看不起你的人的钱
to all those people who thought you were nothing.
天啊  埃弗里  我以前就听过这番话
Jesus, Avery, I've heard this speech before.
你得换点新说辞了
You've got to get new material.
我要说的只是他没给我多少选择的余地
All I'm saying is he didn't leave me much choice.
所以  你只是又一个受害者
So, you're just another victim.
如果你的良心让你如此不安
Well, if your conscience is bothering you so much,
你最好让我来对付这小子
you better let me handle this boy.
你身上还有配枪
You've still got your service weapon.
用来杀人也绰绰有余了
That's pretty good for killing people, too,
就已故的雷米·德博阿那事儿看来
judging by the late Remy Dubois.
如果你坚持的话
If you insist.
带路吧
Lead on.
情况变得更糟糕了
It's getting even worse.
腐朽蔓延的速度更快了
The rot's expanding faster.
它接触到的东西都会变成这样吗
It's like this with everything it touches?
所有的生命
All life.
然后就会留下这幅景象
And this is what it leaves behind.
全都死了
It's all dead.
我们不能待在这
We can't stay here.
我只要采集一份样本就好
I just need to get a sample.
艾比
Abby...
我们得马上走
We gotta go right now.
黑暗力量  它知道我们来了
The darkness, it knows we're here.
我看看  我看看
Let me look. Let me...
那边
There.
快跑  快跑
Go, go, go.
快  快  快
Go, go, go!
来  我帮你系吧
Here. Let me do that.
你知道负责这场盛大演出的人
You realize Sunderland should be running
应该是桑德兰  而不是你
this dog and pony show, not you.
但愿你能再考虑考虑
I wish that you would reconsider
和我一起回学校
and go back to the school with me.
治愈你的阿尔茨海默病的方法
The cure for your Alzheimer's
就在于我在显微镜下所看到的细胞
rests in the cells that I saw under that microscope.
我确定
I know it.
在你的发现
You have a long row to hoe
能治疗我这种病症之前
before your discovery can be tailored
-还有很多问题要解决  -不
- to a condition like mine. - No.
我们有时间
We've got time.
我不接受其它结果
I won't accept anything else.
时候不早了  我得回去了
It's getting late. I gotta go back.
不  不  再给我几分钟
No, no, no, no. Just a couple of more minutes.
马特就是在这个地方看到他的
This is the area where Matt spotted him.
我猜他不会走远的
I'm guessing that he wouldn't have wandered off far.
我们得解决这件事  埃弗里
We gotta get this done, Avery.
如果霍兰真在这里
If Holland's really out here,
我们可以早上再回来找
we could come back in the morning.
等等
Wait.
你看到了吗
Did you see that?
那里有东西在动
You see, there's something moving right there.
-埃弗里  -你觉得我有多有蠢
- Avery. - How stupid do you think I am?
别开枪
Don't!
你在等什么
What are you waiting for?
你在等什么  露西
What are you waiting for, Luce?
你是在等你的搭档出现
You're waiting for your partner to show up,
还是想找个好地方来处理我的尸体
or maybe just looking for a good place to dump my body?
不  把枪放下
No. Put the gun down.
你以为我真的相信
You think I really believe
你说霍兰还活着的鬼话吗
that bullshit about Holland still being alive?
是真的
It's true.
就算是真的  也没有任何区别
Even if it were, it wouldn't make any difference
因为我了解你
'cause I know you.
你是个记仇的人
You don't forget.
你不会原谅我
You don't forgive.
所以  就这样了吗  你就...
So, is that it? You're just...
你就打算朝我开枪吗
You're just gonna shoot me?
给我一个不这么做的理由
You give me one good reason why I shouldn't do that.
因为我是这世上唯一一个了解你的人
Because I'm the only person left on earth who knows you.
因为我是这世上唯一一个理解你的人
Because I'm the only person left on earth who sees you.
我们一起经历了这么多
After everything we've been through.
-我以为...  -你以为什么
- I thought... - What did you think?
我以为你是爱我的
I thought that you loved me.
我是爱你
I do love you.
求你了  埃弗里
Please, Avery.
有那么一瞬间  我还以为你变卦了
For a second, I thought you'd changed your mind.
导航出了点问题
GPS crapped out.
-把他杀了吧  -不不不  别在这
- Let's finish this. - No, no, no, no, not here.
去水里
Out on the water.
我不想冒任何风险
I don't wanna take any chance
留下血迹证据
and leave any blood evidence behind
或者被人发现尸体  好吗
or anybody finding the body, okay?
把这个给我
So, you give me this.
我们致力于与在公司战略  医药  科技和可持续发展领域有独特想法的创新者合作
我们的创新正在改变世界
加入我们  你的创新也能改变世界
领导层
内森·埃勒里
埃勒里先生  我是玛丽亚·桑德兰
Mr. Ellery, Maria Sunderland.
很高兴见到你
It's so nice to meet you.
请进
Please.
我和我丈夫埃弗里十分荣幸
My husband, Avery, and I are so honored
你能来到这里和我们见面
that you came all the way down here to see us.
-一路上还好吗  -很漫长
- How was your trip? - Long.
你们的小镇实在是太偏僻了
Your little town here is pretty far off the beaten path.
如果你喜欢这种风格的话  倒也满别致的
Quaint, though, if you like that sort of thing.
这是路易斯安那州最不为人知的秘密
Well, it's Louisiana's best kept secret.
埃弗里不得不出门办点事
Avery had to run an errand,
但我知道他十分激动能和你分享他的成果
but I know he's so excited to share his results with you.
晚餐还没准备好  但不如先一起
Dinner isn't quite ready yet, but why don't you join me
喝点鸡尾酒  吃点蟹肉沙拉
for a cocktail and some crab maison.
我要伏特加马提尼  滤冰缀果皮
Vodka martini. Up with a twist.
没事的  我们来这边
It's okay. We'll just get over here.
亚历克
Alec?
让我看一眼
Let me see it.
先脱下来
Take this off. Come on.
待在这别动  放松  好吗
Stay right here. Just relax right now, okay?
咬我的是什么东西
What was that thing that bit me?
来自腐朽之中的藤蔓
Some kind of tendril coming from the rot.
什么
What?
这个伤口  它...
It's a wound. It's, uh...
坏死性筋膜炎
It's a necrotizing fasciitis.
一种食肉类细菌
It is a flesh-eating bacteria.
没错  类似的东西
Something like that, yeah.
黑暗力量
The darkness.
艾比  我们得马上去医院
Abby, we need to go to a hospital right now.
我撑不到那时候了
I won't make it to the hospital.
有种植物
There are plants,
中国灯笼草  是一种很有效的抗菌药
Chinese lantern, it's a powerful antiseptic.
这附近没有  听我说
They don't grow around here. Listen to me.
但它们总归长在某个地方
But they grow somewhere. They grow somewhere.
你可以把它们带来
You can bring them.
待在这别动  别动
Stay right here. Stay right here.
把这个咽下去  咽下去
Swallow these. Swallow. Swallow.
看着我  看着我  什么情况
Look at me. Look at me. Yes? What's happening?
没有用  没有用
It's not working. It's not working.
腐朽在反击  好吧
Rot's fighting back. Okay.
腐朽在反击
Rot's fighting back.
他醒了
He's moving.
好吧
Well,
我没想到你有这个胆量
I didn't think you had the guts, boy.
闭嘴
Shut up.
这是个绝佳的地点
This is as good a place as any.
你们他妈想干什么
What the hell's going on here?
再他妈好好想想吧
Second fucking thoughts?
不  这已经板上钉钉了
Oh, no, this is gonna happen.
你把我的马蒂变成了杀人犯  你越界了埃弗里
You turned my Matty into a murderer. You crossed the line, Avery.
你能承担这这个吗  孩子
You sure you can live with this, boy?
承担什么
Live with what?
在你把我像整个镇子一样弄垮之前
Getting rid of a monster like you
除掉你这个恶棍吗
before you drag me down like the rest of this town?
不  我只是想知道
No, I'm just wondering
你能承担杀死亲生父亲的罪行吗
if you could live with killing your own father.
-他在说什么  -没错
- What the hell is he talking about? - That's right.
你以为呢  我会信你的鬼话吗
What did you think? That I was gonna take your word for it?
你说他是别人的种
That he was someone else's child?
第一次见到他时我就感觉到了
I had a feeling the minute I saw him.
贿赂了医生  他们采集了马特的样本
Paid off some doctors. They had Matt's samples.
-是真的吗  -婊子养的
- Is this true? - Son of a bitch.
他也是我儿子
He's my son, too!
-这么多年你一直知道  -猎枪给我
- All these years, you already knew. - Give me the shotgun.
不  你他妈知道  我想要真相
No, you fucking knew? I wanna know the truth!
-猎枪给我  -我想知道真相
- Give me the shotgun! - I wanna know the truth!
别管他妈的猎枪了
Forget about the fucking gun right now!
天杀的
God dammit!
他死了吗  他死了吗  他死了吗
Is he dead? Is he dead? Is he dead?
压住伤口  好吗  我们找人救你
Keep some pressure on this, okay? We'll go get help.
艾比  我懂  我懂
Abby. I know, I know.
-我怎么了  -没事的  放松
- What's happening to me? - It's okay. Just relax.
你的体内有场
It's a war inside of you
腐朽和万物之绿的战争
between the rot and the green.
坚持住  坚持住  你体内有两百种菌类
Hold on, hold on. There's 200 species of flora inside your body.
如果我能让它们都生长并疗愈...
If I could coax them all to grow and to heal...
艾比
Abby.
我再次为埃弗里的迟到表示歉意
Again, I'm so sorry that Avery's been delayed.
不过与此同时  来尝尝我的山核桃派吧
But, in the meantime, you should have a slice of my pecan pie.
山核桃来自于我家地里的核桃树
The nuts are harvested from trees right here on the property.
实话实说  我不是来品尝你的厨艺的
To be frank, I didn't come for the cuisine.
他向我保证会提供重大突破的数据
I was promised data regarding a major breakthrough.
你丈夫调用了所有关系才促成了这场会面
Your husband called in every favor he had to get this meeting,
而现在他却懒得露面吗
and now, he can't be bothered to show?
我真的很感激你抽出时间
I truly appreciate the value of your time.
在审核了秘密会议集团的工作后
And after reviewing the work of the Conclave Group,
特别是有你参与的
and especially your involvement
在莫德四项目
in the Mod Four project.
你怎么知道莫德四的事
How do you know about Mod Four?
虽然我是个小镇姑娘
Well, I may be a small-town girl,
但我还是有些身份显赫的朋友的
but I still have a few friends in high places.
谢谢
Thank you.
既然埃弗里不便出席  娜丁
Since Avery is indisposed, um, Nadine,
或许伍德罗博士可以为我们讲解计划书
perhaps Dr. Woodrue would walk us through the prospectus.
好的
Yes.
没问题
Of course.
请翻到第三页  我们从一种
If you go to page three, you'll see that we began
自然生成的生物有机化合物入手
with a naturally occurring bio-organic compound
该物质的主要构成是木质素和叶绿素
that's heavily comprised of lignin and chlorophyll.
受试病人  我们的第一个实验对象
The patient, our first test subject,
遭受了严重的脑损伤
suffered a severe brain injury,
被诊断为七级昏迷
and was diagnosed level 7 comatose.
但是在注射伍德罗博士的制剂十二小时后
But after less than 12 hours of dosing with Dr. Woodrue's formula,
他完全恢复了意识
he regained complete consciousness
距他受伤过去了两天
two days after his injury.
有意思
Interesting.
我们研究的物质是在我们的实验室
The material we're working with is a living tissue
开发出来的活体组织
developed right here in our laboratory,
它的突变速度比人造的或自然界中的
and has the ability to mutate thousands of times faster
任何已知的东西都要快上千倍
than anything else known to man or nature.
这是你自己做的
You made this yourself?
秘诀就是本地的山核桃
Local pecans, that's the secret.
现在请翻到第七页
Now, if you would please turn to page seven.
艾比
Abby.
好点了吗
Feeling better?
嗯
Yeah.
谢谢你
Thank you.
别客气
Of course.
什么  怎么了
What? What is it?
没事
Nothing.
只是孢子
Just the spores.
快要失效了
They're wearing off.
嗯
Yeah.
好吧
Well...
做一天亚历克还是挺好的
it was fun to be Alec for a day.
过来
Come here.
我们不知道接下来会发生什么
We don't know what's going to happen.
我们只有此时此刻
All we have is right here, right now.
你刚刚救了我的命
You just saved my life.
嗯
Yeah.
你应该好好休息
You should get some rest.
我们成功了
Well, we did it.
全额资金
Full funding.
正经的实验室设备  支持人员
Proper lab equipment, support staff.
终于能够开始了
It's all finally happening.
你将会是第一个受益者
And you'll be the first to benefit.
晚餐吃得开心吗
Did you enjoy dinner?
味道好极了
It was delicious.
我问这个是因为
I only ask because, uh...
你当时很安静
you seemed so quiet.
我当时在享受愉快的时光
I was having a lovely time.
不过餐桌上另一对夫妇是谁
But who was that other couple at the table?
那个男人叫内森·埃勒里
that man was named Nathan Ellery.
他妻子呢
And his wife?
玛丽亚  她叫玛丽亚
Maria. Her name was Maria.
他们很亲切
They seem very nice.
我很累了
I'm very tired.
好的
Of course.
晚安  亲爱的
Goodnight, sweetheart.
坚持住  马蒂
Hang in there, Matty.
见鬼  妈妈  这么多年来你一直骗我
God damn it, Mom. You lied to me all these years.
我犯了个错误  马蒂
I made a mistake, Matty.
-你为什么不能告诉我  -我羞于启齿
- Why couldn't you just tell me, huh? - I was ashamed.
我受不了让埃弗里出现在你的人生中
I couldn't bear the idea of Avery being in your life,
让你把那个可怕的男人当作父亲
of you looking up to that horrible man as your father.
你都是为了我  是吧
You did it all for me, huh?
这边
Over here.
桑德兰公司  秘密会议集团
玛丽亚·桑德兰  内森·埃勒里
-怎么搞的  -我们需要进去
- What the hell? - We need to come in.
天哪  你不能来这里
Jesus Christ, you can't be here.
玛丽亚  马蒂失血过多
Maria, Matt is bleeding out.
-让我们进去  -这又是谁
- Let us in. - Who the hell is this?
这是弗雷德医生  我在船上给他打的电话
That's Doctor Fred. I called him from the boat.
听着  你以为我想来这里吗
Look, you think I wanna be here?
马特受了刀伤  我没法带他去医院
I can't exactly bring Matt to the hospital with a knife wound.
求你了
Please.
好吧  带他去厨房
All right, bring him into the kitchen.
没事的
It's okay.
喝了它  马蒂
Drink it, Matty.
这可不是计划的一部分
This was not part of the plan.
抱歉给你带来不便
Sorry for the inconvenience,
但我也没想到那混蛋会捅我儿子
but I didn't expect the bastard to stab my son.
你让他们签下合同了吗
Did you get them to sign the paperwork?
签了
Yes.
伍德罗尽力了
Woodrue did his part,
然后山核桃派搞定了对方
and the pecan pie sealed the deal.
埃弗里呢
Avery.
他死了
He's dead.
干杯  妹子  成功了
Cheer up, buttercup. It worked.
公司是你的了
The company is yours.
原谅我无法为丈夫的死欣喜若狂
Forgive me if I don't gloat over the death of my husband.
那些谎言与操纵
All the lies and manipulation.
很久没喝过了
It's been a while.
好吧  记得去警局
Yeah, well, remember to go by the station
填失踪人口报告
and file a missing person's report.
我应该派个人去
I should send someone out.
我不想再看到你了
I don't wanna see you again.
我们有共同目标  露西莉亚
We had a common goal, Lucilia,
既然目标达成了  我希望你从我的人生中消失
and now that it's done, I want you out of my life.
你总是自觉高我一等
You always did think you were better than me.
走之前一定要把血迹都擦干净
Make sure you clean up all this blood before you go.
明天早上我要看到厨房一尘不染
I want my kitchen spotless in the morning.
你该走了
You should go.
我明天再来
I'll come back tomorrow.
你不应该再来了
I don't think that's a good idea.
我一直在想  也许我变成
I've been thinking, maybe there's a reason
现在这样是有原因的  比如...
I've become what I am, you know? Like...
比如我身处某个更宏大的计划中
Like I'm the part of some larger plan.
你说的...
What, um...
你说的是什么样的计划
What kind of plan are we talking about?
我不知道  但是...
I don't know, but it's...
它比你我更加重要
It's bigger than you and me.
你手臂中的对抗
That fight we saw in your arm,
就在我们身边
it's all around us.
遍布这片沼泽
Here, in this swamp.
而且是一场生死决斗
And it's a fight to the death.
也许我被变成这个怪物
Maybe I've been turned into this thing
是为了成为这场战斗中的战士
to be a warrior in that battle.
好吧  但亚历克·霍兰该怎么办呢
Okay, but where does all that leave Alec Holland?
亚历克救不了你的命
Alec couldn't have saved your life.
只有我变成的怪物能做到
Only this thing that I've become could do that.
你已经尽你所能了  艾比
You've done what you can, Abby.
谢谢你
Thank you.
但这是我的宿命  不是你的
But it's not your destiny, it's mine.
你还有你的生活  应该好好享受
And you have a life to live, and you need to go live it.
如果要作战  我想与你并肩战斗
If there is a battle to fight, I wanna fight it with you.
不行
No.
亚历克
Alec.
你在这里太危险了
It's too dangerous for you out here.
这是我的地盘
This is my place.
我想要你离开  别再回来了
I want you to go, and don't come back here again.
艾比  你去哪了
Abby, where you been?
我去向一位朋友道别了
I've been saying goodbye to a friend.
你是指亚历克
You mean Alec?
对
Yeah.
他快丧失希望了  莉兹
He's losing hope, Liz.
我
I, um...
我从沼泽采集了一份可能有用的样本
I pulled a sample from the swamp that I think might help,
但我需要利用疾控中心的全部资源来进行调查
but I'm gonna need the full resources of the CDC to investigate.
也就是说
Meaning?
我要回亚特兰大
I'm going back to Atlanta.
-今晚就走  -亚特兰大
- Tonight. - Atlanta?
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我什么都不能确定了
Well, I'm not sure about anything anymore,
但我必须帮他
but I have to help him.
我确定  我必须找出办法
I know it. I have to find a way.
欢迎来到玛雷